Alright
In this lesson, we'll cover the basics of
object-oriented programming
Let's start by creating a project
Then, let's make a copy of this project
Lesson Eight
Next, let's open the project
Moving forward, we won't do it this way
From now on, I'll just open the project directly
Let's not waste time when opening a new project.
Now, let's take a look at this class.
This is about object-oriented programming.
Let me explain it.
Python is based on object-oriented programming.
If you're transitioning from Java,
or from C++,
you should find it quite easy to understand.
Because both of them have the concept of classes.
If you're transitioning from C
you might need some time to adapt
to the shift in thinking
and if you don’t have a programming background, don’t worry
just follow this approach
first, let's introduce the concept of classes
let's copy this over first
we'll go through this example
first, we'll overwrite everything here
Because we're still just learning the basics here
Just the fundamentals
We need to study this in a more independent way
To make it clearer
Let's delete everything from before
Let's talk about classes
The concept of classes
First, a class is defined using the class keyword
This is a keyword
Then the name of this class
you can name it anything you like
But we have an established convention
the first letter of a class name is capitalized
it's not mandatory
But something established by usage
this is a standard we follow
and you don't need to remember the colon part
basically, the 'class' keyword is what defines a class
Then there's this method here
which is defined using def as the INIT method
This method is quite special
It gets called automatically when an instance of the class is created
When the class is instantiated
it will be called automatically
In this method, self is a fixed parameter
It refers to the instance of the class
the object itself
Here, it refers to this cf
It's an implicit pass
We don't need to do it manually
It gets passed when we call it
It's an implicit pass
But it must be written here
Just write it here
Then it essentially acts as an instantiation of the class object
Through the object itself
It can call itself to assign values.
We pass in this thing to assign.
Assign it over.
This is our initialization.
It's like when the class is created.
It automatically calls this initialization function.
To initialize the properties inside.
These properties are encapsulated by us.
This is an encapsulation feature in object-oriented programming.
The encapsulation assigns this parameter.
This is when we instantiate a class.
Here, we are essentially creating an object instance.
Ultimately, we instantiate a dog object.
The object takes these two parameters.
Then it gets instantiated.
This becomes an object.
Inside, it encapsulates a method.
We can call this method through the object.
What is this method for?
This method is for printing.
It’s to accomplish a task.
Here, it prints the information about this dog.
It’s like the dog’s information, right?
What’s its name?
How old is it?
This printing method.
And this is the information about its bark.
Look at how it passes the movie parameter in the method call.
This movie parameter is passed as self ft.
It refers to the object itself.
And here, it's part of the tutorial.
The tutorial basically just prints out some information.
Let's run it now.
It prints this out.
How does it do that?
First, when we call the method,
First, we instantiate this class.
During instantiation, it automatically takes what we pass in.
You can see it has three here, right?
But we only need to pass two.
This is implicitly passed in.
Passed in.
When we instantiate here,
The two we pass in,
Will eventually be assigned here.
We assign it to the object itself
This way, it's essentially initialized
So, this dog is an instance, right?
With an instance, we can call its methods
For example, we call this method
It prints this message, right?
Then we call this method
It also prints
Its bark
Look, he just printed a little yellow dog, right?
This is kind of its
It's like the most basic class.
Next, let's take a look at inheriting this class.
Let's copy this section over.
This part will be a bit more complex.
Then we'll paste this here first.
Let's take a look at
First, we need to use at t and hit Enter.
Let's import a
We're essentially including, like in C language,
that includes header files, right?
We import this library,
and ABC is also included here,
so we'll also import ABC with this comma,
like this,
this way, our class is,
essentially inheriting from ABC
Then this modifier is added here.
This modifier indicates that
This method is an abstract method.
This is a bit of a chicken rib.
It's like the chicken rib of the animal.
Right here.
This is the chicken rib of the animal.
It represents an animal.
A most basic class.
This class cannot be instantiated.
You can't instantiate this class on its own.
Because it has abstract methods.
Abstract methods must be implemented by a subclass.
Otherwise, you won't be able to call this method.
These are abstract methods.
The writing of abstract methods,
First, you need to inherit from the ABC class.
Then, you add the decorator.
Let's go through it
Don't try to memorize it
You don't need to remember this
It's just the general idea
It's enough to know what it means
You'll naturally remember it after writing more
And this sound here
Because each animal has a different call
But I'll print out the information
This is the information I print every time, right?
I just print the name and age, right?
Print this on Monday.
Of course, you can override it in your subclass.
This method works as well.
But in most cases, we don't need to override it.
This way, it can be reused, right?
That's one of the benefits of inheritance.
Inheritance provides this advantage.
We can implement some common methods in the parent class.
After authentication in the parent class,
the subclasses don't need to implement these common methods.
Right?
In this case,
if this has to be an abstract method,
it must be implemented when the subclass inherits.
The syntax is written like this,
which means it's a placeholder.
This part doesn't need to be implemented.
This method is about what the animal is called.
It's about peptides.
It's essentially peptides.
We don't implement this part.
Then let's move on to the next part.
This is like defining a redundant feature.
The animal class.
This class is a bit special.
It cannot be instantiated.
Then let's give it a try.
This class itself, the class we just worked on, the Dog class.
We can instantiate it, right?
Let's instantiate it here and take a look.
See what happens.
First, the value passed here is this value, correct?
And at this point, we'll
add this.
Let's add this one then.
Then let's call this method and see.
Call the method inside this one.
You see, the AI won't write this for you.
Because it knows this will definitely throw an error.
See, it's throwing an error, right?
It's throwing an error.
It can't be instantiated, right?
It's an abstract method.
An abstract method must be implemented by a subclass.
It has to be implemented.
The subclass needs to implement its method.
So this won't work.
Let's move on to the next one.
Let's look at this one.
Because the dog is an animal, right?
It can inherit from its superclass.
He has some unique attributes.
But he belongs to the animal category, right?
So he inherits some characteristics of animals.
This is the relationship of inheritance.
This is what inheritance means.
This is the inherited parent class.
It's like he has inherited some traits.
But you also have, uh,
You have some new characteristics, right?
There are some new genetic images as well
or something like that
there are some new things
but in animals, there are definitely some attributes
common attributes
like tutorials, for instance
they all have the ability to make sounds
but each tutorial is different
right?
This is like, you know, what's inside it, um
It's the information, right?
The information is basically the name
How old they are
These are all standard, right?
So this would be placed in the parent class
Then let's look at what happens when the subclass inherits from it
The sound method must be implemented
If you don't implement it, it will throw an error
You don't implement this
Then it won't work when you instantiate it
Let's take a look at the instantiation here
We'll set this equal to
Then we'll call it
Let's check this out
Here, it throws the same error, right?
It has to go and
It must go and implement that
An abstract method of the parent class
This is its polymorphism
Let's print this out here
Now let's instantiate and give it a try
This instance is Wangcai
Then print his information
This is calling the parent class
And then let's print out his tutorial
Alright
There's no error now
Let's take a look at this part
He instantiates it like this, right?
Instantiation
Now let's check this out
Why is the value passed here
Why can it print here
We didn't pass it, did we?
Why is it like this
But here we use this method
This represents the superclass
This notation represents the superclass
You need to remember that
This notation means this
This part can use a method to call
The superclass's initializer, right?
Here we use this keyword
This is also a keyword
Then it calls the method of its parent class
The parent class initializes NEMO and the edge
Then it calls the subclass
This is the subclass
Because this object is passed in
Representing this object, right
The subclass also gets initialized
When you finally call the info method of the parent class
It prints out what you have passed in
Because the parent class passed these two parameters.
That's why it can print.
It can print Wangcai, right?
He goes 'wang wang wang'.
This is Wangcai, right?
You passed Wangcai and the age of three, right?
This is its inheritance relationship.
This is why we use inheritance.
It's because there are some common elements.
We can write an accumulation function.
And there are many others that we can use.
But we need to inherit from its less useful parts, though.
To inherit some of its general methods.
That’s the idea.
This involves shifting your programming mindset.
You don’t have to know exactly how to write it at first.
But you need to shift your mindset.
So you understand there is such a mindset.
You'll figure out the specifics when the time comes.
Just search for it then.
Right?
You can search with AI as well.
Or you can search on Baidu.
Now, you can just search with AI.
It will even write it out for you.
But you need to know what you're writing about.
You don't have to write every single word yourself.
But you should have a general idea of what he writes.
This is perfectly fine.
You can start learning this way.
As you learn more over time,
you'll naturally understand, right?
Now let's look at the concept of introducing multiple generations.
The concept of polypeptides.
Let's copy this line of code over.
And again, we'll overwrite this.
Then let's check the error message.
This error also occurs when you include the header file.
The file is 'at' plus Enter.
It will automatically do it for us.
Similarly, for ABCABC,
You can also use 'ADD' and press Enter to import.
It will automatically import it.
Let's practice here first.
See if there are any errors.
No errors here.
Then let's see why it's called a polypeptide.
First of all, similarly here,
we still use an abstract, uh,
define an abstract method,
the abstract class approach,
and it serves as a base class for accumulation.
This part is the same as the previous one,
the same as the inheritance one.
Then, this part is the same here.
Abstract methods.
Here, we have two that inherit from it.
This is an animal, right?
And a dog is also an animal.
This cat is also an animal, right?
So both are animals.
They inherit from the same parent class.
And when the dog inherits,
He simply calls the constructor method of the superclass.
This is known as a constructor function.
It involves calling the constructor of the superclass.
In this case, it hasn’t been initialized itself.
Because this is just a tutorial.
I didn’t print any information.
So, printing information here is fine.
But it’s okay not to initialize it here.
Since you’re not calling any of its properties here.
NEMO, well, his age, right?
So, this place, you don't need to initialize this subclass
It's fine
Then, for our other class, the cat class
It also inherits from the animal class
It has an additional property here
This is perfectly acceptable
It has an extra property
You just need to pass one more
It's no problem
Then, it also overrides this method
This one is mandatory to override
Then, why is this polymorphism
First, we created two instances
One is an instance of a dog
The other is an instance of a cat
Here, we demonstrate polymorphism
That's it
We put the dog's strength and the cat's strength
into an array, right?
You can think of it as putting them into an array
and then referencing them through a variable
using a for loop
to retrieve them
As you can see when retrieving them
These are essentially two different classes, right?
But here, as an array, they are treated as one class
So this is polymorphism.
It means the same variable can belong to different classes.
But it can be called in the same way.
This is what polymorphism is about.
Yeah, you can understand it that way.
This is like an animal cage.
It contains dogs and cats.
When it runs specifically,
It will dynamically bind whether it is a dog or a cat.
That's the idea.
Polymorphism,
this is an example of polymorphism.
This is all part of object-oriented programming.
Let's review this.
Let's go over it again.
First, we introduce the concept of a class.
The concept of a class is introduced here.
This is something we don't have in C language.
So you might need to shift your thinking a bit.
Classes are the foundation of object-oriented programming.
Everything is treated as an object.
Inheritance is used to encapsulate common elements,
like shared attributes,
for example, between animals,
we encapsulate common attributes into a base class.
Specific animals then inherit from this base class.
This way, we write less code.
Otherwise, if you print something,
you'd have to write the print function in each class.
That would be redundant and meaningless, right?
So we can do it this way,
create a base class and inherit from it, right?
Here, the idea of polymorphism is introduced,
so that calling methods later is more convenient.
We can call methods through polymorphism.
Otherwise, you'd have to instantiate each class individually and call them separately.
That would be more complicated.
With polymorphism, it's more straightforward.
Just get a feel for it.
It's like this,
if you can't fully understand it at first, that's okay.
Just get the general idea.
We can continue learning from there.
Alright, that's it for this lesson.